[♪ opening theme song playing]
♪
As of late, Genau here
has been without a companion.
His partner was killed
in battle.
You shall replace him,
and slay demons
with Genau up north.
I'm eager to work with you.
It's an honor.
The north is deadly.
As illustrated by my partner,
loss of life is common.
Do not cost me mine.
Shake her hand.
[pigeons cooing]
[GENAU]
Methode, do you believe
that you're a good person
at your core?
[METHODE] I'm not sure
that I understand what you mean.
My previous partner
was a good person,
and the exact opposite of me.
He would risk body and mind
for complete strangers
without a second thought.
♪
He was so boisterous,
so full of smiles.
He treated me as you would
an old friend.
Wherever we went,
people were drawn
to his magnetic personality.
He was a fool.
[exclaims softly]
♪
He rescued a child
at the cost of his life.
And at the cost
of slaying the demon.
His decision was foolish
and reckless,
and I would never have done
the same.
What is one more life forsaken?
All I can think to say is,
"Why me?"
What do you mean?
Why was I chosen
to work with you?
I have no idea.
That was
Mistress Serie's ruling.
I've noticed a key similarity
in the first-class mages
who get dispatched
to the Northern Plateau.
Most crave violence
like water or air.
I agree, you're an odd choice.
Übel would've been a better fit
for the typical mold.
It doesn't matter.
No decent person
harbors desire for bloodshed.
Whatever you do,
do not end up like me.
[fire crackling]
[FRIEREN] Let's go over
the information we've compiled
before we begin our search.
[METHODE] Very well.
Based on traces of mana
and the variety of damage dealt,
we can conclude
four primary demons
led the attack.
All four of them have vanished
from the area.
That's almost one
for each of us.
And the strongest of the unit
is a demon general.
It wields four swords.
That's how
it killed the knights.
What makes
a demon general special?
They are demon warriors
of the highest caliber.
Their fighting style involves
enhancing their
physical capabilities
with powerful magic.
They can be quite devoted
to their craft,
unafraid to spend centuries
mastering their martial skills.
There were generals
in the Demon King's army
that made Eisen
look like a beginner.
You're kidding me.
This is hardly a joking matter.
Keep in mind,
it is likely the beast's
appearance is far from human.
You say that like it's gonna
make things even worse.
Have you ever fought a swordsman
who's trained for lifetimes
and wields four swords at once?
I can't say that I have.
The same is true for me.
And it was true
for those knights
until they met their end.
♪
[JUNG] Lord Revolte.
Fresh prey
is squirming around in our net.
A tasty meal rich in mana.
We've got one warrior
and four mages,
and three of them
are first-class.
I have no doubt
we can handle that many.
Shall we make a move?
[REVOLTE] No.
They are stronger
than you suggest.
We will wait for them
to split up.
[JUNG] Do you think they would
do that, Lord Revolte?
From what I can tell,
they seem rather guarded.
[REVOLTE]
I am certain of it.
The time we spent
slaughtering the villagers
is about to pay off.
There is a common theme.
A fatal flaw shared by many men
we have encountered
on our path of destruction.
Know what it is?
Well, now you have to tell me,
my lord.
[chuckles]
[FRIEREN] Let the hunt begin.
We're as ready as we'll ever be.
Our first stop should be
the abandoned fort
you told us about up north.
It's a strong lead.
In my experience,
demons often hole up
in places like that.
[GENAU] Wait.
The Chivalric Order of Norm
will come for the bodies.
Someone should see
to their safety.
I'll remain behind.
Humans have a curious habit
of remaining in villages
to protect the corpses
of their fallen.
[gasps]
That's curious indeed.
So why do they do it?
[REVOLTE] We don't need
to know the reason.
[JUNG]
Huh. But it's so interesting.
I'd love to spend just a moment
in their minds.
[REVOLTE] Sounds like
a rather dull place to me.
You are very strange.
Humans are so volatile.
They'll behave
with perfect reason
and then toss it all
to the wind.
Don't you want to know why
they can be so irrational?
[REVOLTE]
That is simply how they are.
There's nothing more to it.
I am not interested
in questions of "why."
Though, there is one.
An eccentric demon
who has made it his life's work
to study the whims of mankind.
There's really
someone like that?
That's amazing! You have
to tell me more about them.
Only if you
make yourself useful.
[JUNG] Is that a yes?
You owe me now, Lord Revolte.
I won't forget!
[METHODE]
You'll stay here by yourself?
[GENAU]
It shouldn't be much longer
before they arrive.
I'll meet up with you
once the bodies
have been collected
and the Order is on their way.
Until then.
I should hang back with you.
Do you know
how foolish you sound?
Your party is on the path
to challenge a skilled foe.
They will require a frontliner.
Maybe, but you'll need one too.
What if the demons use this
as their chance to return?
Not an issue.
I am perfectly capable
of defending myself
without help from you.
[STARK] Trust me.
So are Frieren than the others.
Perhaps, but only to a point.
[STARK] Yeah, I hear you.
But if things get bad,
can't you just run away?
I suppose so.
You don't have that choice.
There's no shot
you abandon the village.
♪
They are dead.
There's no one left to abandon.
If you felt that way,
then you wouldn't stay here
to protect their bodies.
[Genau sighs] Suit yourself.
♪
[footsteps]
You're a fool,
but you're a good person, Stark.
Uh...
[GENAU] I've known
several people like you.
They tend to lead short lives.
[STARK] For what it's worth,
you seem like a good person
to me, too.
♪
You're still trying
to defend the village
even after it's been destroyed.
I couldn't do that.
[GENAU] I assure you,
I'm not a good person.
Quite the opposite, really.
My sole priority for some time
has been bringing peace
to the northern lands.
I've killed and forsaken many
in my pursuit,
all with a resounding numbness.
Perhaps this is what I deserve.
Death has become
a regular part of my day.
I feel no tinge of sadness.
My hometown is in ruins,
yet I cannot shed a tear.
There was no tug on my soul
to protect the village.
Staying back seemed
the proper thing to do.
There's no undoing the hurt
I've caused,
yet I am wasting energy
in some desperate attempt.
Listen, Stark,
dangerous as it is,
there are many who call
this plateau their home.
[FRIEREN] Going forward,
we should avoid
using long-range detection.
If they're skilled,
they'll quickly trace it
back to us.
[FERN] Right.
Though caution's key,
we still have a while to go
before we reach the fort.
The demons won't notice
a little chat.
[Methode chuckles]
You're sure it's worth the risk?
We'll be more fluid in battle
if tensions are low.
Not a solitary care.
[FRIEREN] Good communication
is the foundation
upon which one can build a team.
Ponder that, young lady.
[FERN] Uh-huh.
Then, in the spirit of openness,
may I inquire about
a quick head pat?
[FERN] I can't believe you
said that with a straight face.
My trouble is,
I have an innate desire
to coddle and cuddle
adorable creatures.
But dear Mistress Serie
is scarcely one to capitulate.
And in the rare instance
she agrees,
she looks horribly displeased.
[FRIEREN]
I fear I would look the same.
If age plays into this,
know that I am your elder
by many a century.
Besides, my head
is not for patting.
That's right. She may be cute,
but she's a mature adult.
Petting is out of the question.
Miss Frieren.
This grimoire contains a spell
that prevents any shell
from falling in the bowl
when you're cracking eggs.
Pet me to your heart's content.
Mistress Frieren!
♪
[Methode chuckles, hums]
Thank you
for being a good sport.
I rarely get to indulge
for long stretches.
You're allowed ten minutes a day
and not a second more.
That's all?
[chuckles]
Final question, Miss Frieren.
Before we locate the enemy,
may I please give you a hug?
Mistress Serie
has always denied my requests.
You can do whatever you want.
[METHODE]
Adorable and generous.
[Fern groans softly]
[Fern grunts softly]
[FRIEREN] Fern. Stand down.
Hey! Stop that!
I'm of no use to you
split in two.
Was that them?
They've picked out
exactly where we are.
This battle's begun
whether we're ready or not.
Typical demons.
They're bloodthirsty
and unafraid.
If they can tell where we are,
they can also tell
that we're powerful mages.
And they're wholly unfazed.
They have noticed us.
Right. Shall we begin?
Nebeladora.
[FRIEREN]
It's a fog made of mana.
They're blocking our vision
and our mana detection.
Our separation
was surely intentional.
They're quite skilled.
Choose your foe.
I would like the tallest one.
There's a peculiar aura
about her.
She should be fun.
And that leaves the other two
to me.
Remain on high alert
for attacks from above.
-Mistress Frieren?
-Yes, Fern.
Both of those demons
were flying.
The demons we've fought before
could fly, too.
They're using flying magic,
right?
I have explained this.
Until just forty years ago,
demons ruled the skies.
Those talents have not dwindled.
Sure, but you also said demons
only study one type of magic.
Do you think of walking
as a special,
attention-demanding ability?
It's the same principle.
Flying is so second nature
to them.
It isn't magic anymore.
When fighting a demon,
it's safe to assume
they will use the skies.
I had a feeling
our opponents would be
accustomed to battle.
They're as comfortable
as members
of the Demon King's army.
-[loud slashing]
-[Fern gasps]
♪
Our cuddler has engaged
the enemy.
Ready?
I'll leave this fight to you.
You won't help?
As I recall,
this job was assigned
to three first-class mages.
And you are
the only first-class mage I see.
Is now really
a good time for that?
It's as good of a time as any.
You can defeat it.
[Fern gasps]
Told you.
Oh?
You know that was a fluke.
I only reacted in time
because you pointed it out.
I couldn't detect the attack
at all.
I'm severely outclassed.
I have to disagree
with you on that.
Of the first-class mages
I've met,
few are as dedicated
to the fundamentals as you.
You trust me.
And I say you can win this.
-[Fern grunts softly]
-[wind blows]
I caught some fish.
Want a late night snack?
[GENAU] I should pass.
Methode would be angry with me.
She says it's unhealthy
to eat late at night.
[STARK]
Oh, yeah? More for me then.
[soft clattering]
I love eating midnight snacks,
but I've gotta be sneaky.
Uh...
Swear you won't tell on me
to Fern?
Fine.
Seems we're fighting
many of the same demons.
[STARK] Hey, Genau?
You know the demon
who attacked this village,
don't you?
[GENAU] Demons that fight
with four swords
are hardly common.
The Divine Revolte
is the demon who ended
my partner's life.
I'm sure he's strong,
but that name's a bit much.
[GENAU] It comes
from the four swords
he created using magic.
He can freely change
their weight.
Sometimes, they're as light
as feathers.
Other times, they are
heavy boulders waiting to fall.
The unknown is
what makes them so dangerous.
They're called
the Divine Cleaving Swords
after the famous blade
that split mountains
during mythical times.
He can change them
to win every fight.
Light and sharp
or heavy and destructive.
And every shade in between.
Magic creates objects
that have no business
existing in this world.
It can take an eon
of murderous intent
and give it a physical form
in a weapon.
Demons create these armaments
to kill humans by the score.
Far more than necessary
for their sustenance,
as if to test their new toys.
[grunts]
Stark.
Glad I hung back, aren't you?
It's quite fast.
Brace yourself.
[rumbling]
[Stark grunts]
♪
That's four swords.
One warrior
and one first-class mage
left behind as guards.
That was
a foolishly human decision.
So predictable.
That's Revolte.
Yeah, I had a feeling.
I suppose there is no need
to introduce myself.
The warrior is someone new.
But you look rather familiar
to me, first-class mage.
Who are you?
No point in waiting around.
If you can, avoid taking
his attacks head on.
If he feels compelled,
he could flatten you
in a single blow.
I asked who you are, mage.
Tell me.
I do not talk to pests
before I exterminate them.
I see no good reason
to declare my name.
And I do not appreciate
being belittled to a pest.
We both speak the same language
and know the same words.
But if you refuse to use them,
I suppose there are simpler ways
we can communicate.
I, too, shall exterminate
the pests
that stand before me.
If I can't take
his attacks head on,
then what should I do?
A skilled warrior can
deflect blows, can he not?
[grunts] I mean, yeah, but...
Then I can't protect you!
I can assure you,
I don't need protecting.
Close-quarters combat
is actually a specialty of mine.
[Stark grunts]
♪
[Genau grunts]
His magic and mine
are not as different
as you might suspect.
I can also create objects
that shouldn't exist.
Now, Digardnacht.
A nameless mage with a spell
to manipulate niello wings.
Interesting.
[chuckles]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[FRIEREN]
It's nice to watch from afar.
[METHODE] I cannot find
the slightest opening.
-[JUNG] I did it!
-[overlapping chatter]
[REVOLTE] I shall put you
out of your misery.
[GENAU]
He met a magnificent end.